Thomas Seropian

French nationality, Indefinite leave to remain Currently based in London, United Kingdom

thomas@seropian.io https://uk.linkedin.com/in/tseropian

Senior / Lead Software Engineer

Profile

I am a senior software engineer, with more than a decade of experience managing complex technology projects for various types of organisations. I am managing the delivery of both end-user and backend applications for a med-tech startup. Prior to that, I was the technical lead for an international media group, managing websites infrastructure for supporting millions of unique monthly users. Prior to that, I built and managing a team of 5 technologists for a non-profit organisation in London and remotely.

Skill set: building web applications, leading technical teams. System designing. Leadership, communication with technical and non-technical audiences. Strong sense of innovation. Design and creation of user stories. Research, prototyping. Flexibility. Project management. Hiring, mentoring and performance management.

Work experience

Lead Software Engineer / Head of Engineering for a med-tech startup **Skin Analytics,** London, United Kingdom – October 2017 to May 2019 (www.skin-analytics.com)

→ Responsible for clients, internal and commercial applications and infrastructures
Managing end-user applications and infrastructure, including release processes and improvements. Designing, defining roadmaps, scoping new requirements. Writing code. Hiring and leading technical team (both in house and contractors), day to day management, code reviews and testing with a focus on security.
Leading design and delivery of a commercial Software as a Medical Device (IEC 62304) cloud-based API.

→ <u>Technology:</u> AWS, Node.js, Angular 7, TypeScript, React, React Native, MySQL, MongoDB, Docker, Ansible

Mentor and Advisor, since 2018

- → Mentoring for the tech lead curriculum for the main french online education platform Open Classrooms
- → Coach and advisor for a startup challenge about <u>Blockchain and social impact</u>

Technical Lead (contract based) for an international online media publishing group **Jamie Oliver,** London, United Kingdom – February to September 2017 (www.jamieoliver.com)

- → Responsible for infrastructure and web applications supporting Jamie's online presence.

 Scoping and delivering new features and APIs. Writing code and tests. Managing contractors. Managing AWS based infrastructure, including release processes, optimisations, and improvements.
- → <u>Technology:</u> AWS, Node.js, TypeScript, PHP (Laravel), RESTful APIs, Redis, Solr, Vue.js, WordPress, Varnish.

Technology Manager for an international NGO

Internews London, United Kingdom – April 2015 to December 2016 (www.internews.org)

- → Leading the design, development, and delivery of innovation and technology components

 Working with a multidisciplinary team supporting local start-ups among the most repressive regimes.

 Leading on delivering news publishing apps. Managing activities' budgets. Speaking at conferences and events.
- → Managing technology team and resources across multiple projects (8 countries)

 Overseeing the recruitment and day-to-day managing a team of 4 technologists. Ensuring planning, setting priorities, agreeing on detailed work plans, budgets, and schedules. Coaching and mentoring team members. Agile delivery. Responsible for technical architecture and roadmap. Focus on scalability & security.
- → <u>Technology:</u> Node.js, PHP (Laravel), Wordpress, Drupal (7/8), Ansible, Nginx, OpenVPN, encryption.

Freelance Consultant in open source technologies

Self-Employed London, United Kingdom – April 2014 to September 2015 (www.seropian.io)

- → Designing & developing web applications and prototypes for various range of clients
- → Areas of work: Drupal, E-Commerce, intranet applications, Infrastructure management.

Designed and built a subscription-based application, including automated online payments. Agile Prototyping. Developed Intranet and extranet applications including import/export modules for a booking agent. Defined and prioritized user stories in close collaboration with different team members.

→ <u>Technology:</u> Node.js, Drupal 7, Drush, Github, Selenium HQ, Vagrant, RESTful APIs.

ICT Projects Manager / Web Application Engineer for an international NGO

Internews Paris, France / London, United Kingdom - March 2009 to March 2014 (www.internews.eu)

→ Online freedom of expression, support of local media, digital security

Designing, developing & supporting multilingual web applications, custom modules. Integration with social network (Twitter, Facebook) APIs. Writing documentation for users. Managing localizations, training & support.

Writing user stories & specifications. Managing external contractors and developers, resources & infrastructures: Deployment and monitoring of servers, secure hosting & video platforms. Building, delivering and facilitating training & trainers on ICT topics. Training of trainers on website building and digital security (West Africa, MENA).

→ <u>Technology</u>: Drupal, Mediawiki, XML/JSON, PHP (OOP, MVC), MySQL, Solr, AWS, Collectd, Vagrant, Nginx.

Software Engineer for a social networking service designed for a family use **Hellotipi.com** Paris, France – February 2008 to January 2009 (www.hellotipi.com)

- → Designed, developed and implemented new features for the service.

 Video sharing. Photo tagging. Revamped the registration process. Multilingual support. Managed client support.

 □
- → <u>Technology</u>: Debian, Apache, MySQL, PHP5 (OOP, MVC), XML, Jquery, Ffmpeg.

ICT Projects Manager for a local NGO in Armenia

Fondation KASA Yerevan, Armenia - March 2006 to September 2007 (www.kasa.am)

Coordinated Computer training in youth training centres. Developed activities in 2 major cities. Managed the recruitment of the local team. Provided technical support for training & social programs. Participated in feasibility studies & design for countrywide projects.

Assistant Projects Manager for e-training IT projects for an international training centre **Valeo Thermal Systems** Paris, France – March 2005 to February 2006 (www.valeo.com) Designed & implemented tools for course supports creation (virtual classes, e-learning modules).

Education

MSc in Computer Sciences and Innovation

Ecole Supérieure d'Informatique, Electronique, Automatique Paris, France

5 years engineering school in information technologies & electronics (www.esiea.fr).

 \rightarrow Graduated with first class honours.

Foreign languages

French: Mother tongue English: Fluent Spanish: Basic level Arabic: Beginner